Herman Langinger Music Publishing Files
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Project Files, 1889-1972 (Box 1-12)
  - Kerr, Harrison
    - Notations on a sensitized plate: for voice, clarinet, string quartet, and piano, 1939, Poem by Cary Ross.
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Khachaturian, Aram
    - Dance no. 3 (piano), 1934
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Kodály, Zoltán
    - Zongora muzsika: ten pieces for solo piano, 1945
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/9)
  - La Violette, Wesley
    - Largo lyrico (string orchestra, timpani, harp or piano), 1944
      - Printed score and parts (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Luening, Otto
    - Eight preludes for piano, 1942
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Only themselves understand themselves, 1934, Text by Walt Whitman.
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/11)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/11)
  - McKay, George Frederick
    - Dance suite no. 2 (piano), 1940
      - Printed score (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 2/6)
  - McPhee, Colin
    - Four Iroquois dances (orchestra), 1945
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Miaskovsky, Nikolai
    - Fragment lyrique (orchestra), 1934
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Mignone, Francisco
    - Lenda sertaeja: no. 9 (piano), 1942
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Correspondence, Includes five letters from Henry Cowell. (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Milhaud, Darius
    - Danses de Jacarémirim: for violin and piano, 1945
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Correspondence, One letter from Milhaud regarding corrections. (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Le bal martiniquais (2 pianos), 1944
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Le bal martiniquais (orchestra), 1945
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/4)
    - La liberation des Antilles. No. 1: Bonjour messieurs les liberateurs (voice, piano), 1944, Text by Henri et Hélène Hoppenot.
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Typescipt of text (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Monod, Jacques-Louis
    - Passacaille, op. 1: for soprano and seven instruments, 1952
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 7/6)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Moross, Jerome
    - Biguine (orchestra), 1935
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Mossolov, Alexander Vassilievich
    - A Turkmenian lullaby: for chorus a capella, 1934
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Nancarrow, Conlon
    - Blues for piano, 1938
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Prelude (piano), 1938
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Rhythm study no. 1: for player-piano, 1951
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Correspondence, One letter from Vladimir Ussachevsky. (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Toccata for violin and piano, 1938
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Newell, Sara
    - Salute to spring (voice, piano), 1945, Words by John Milton.
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Paz, Juan Carlos
    - 3a composición en los 12 tonos, op. 32 ( B♭ clarinet, piano), 1943
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Clarinet part (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Perl, Lothar
    - Four American variations on a theme by Paganini (piano), 1947
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Perle, George
    - Hebrew melodies: for unaccompanied cello, op. 19, 1945
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Quartet no. 3, op. 21 (string quartet), 1948
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Pisk, Paul A.
    - Five sketches for piano, op. 39, 1942
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Polovinkin, Leonid Alexeyevich
    - Humoresque philosophique (piano), 1933
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Prausnitz, Frederik
    - Episode (orchestra), 1949
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Price, Florence B.
    - Dances in the Canebrakes: for piano, 1953
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 8/5)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Purcell, Henry
    - Two preludes for piano, 1945, Transcribed by Béla Bartók.
      - Publisher's proofs (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Printed scores (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Riegger, Wallingford
    - Duos for three woodwinds, 1944
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Suite for flute alone, 1930
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Roldán, Amadeo
    - Motivos de son: eight Cuban songs for voice and small orchestra, 1935
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Publisher's proof, Nos. 1, 5, and 8 only. (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Printed score, Nos. 1, 5, and 8 only. (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Rózsa, Béla
    - Sonate pour piano, 1929
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Rudhyar, Dane
    - Granites (piano), 1929
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Sinfonietta (orchestra), 1934
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Notes and corrections (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Ruggles, Carl
    - Angels: for brass or strings, 1925
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Evocation. No. 4, 1944
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Correspondence, Includes one letter from Ruggles. (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Evocations: four chants for piano, 1954
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Printed scores, One score is the revised version, with added changes and dedications. (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Evocations: three chants for piano, 1943
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Organum: for orchestra (piano), 1947, Arrangement by John Kirkpatrick.
      - Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Sun-treader (orchestra), 1934
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/1)
      - Corrections (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Russell, Bill
    - Three dance movements (percussion ensemble), 1933
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Ruyneman, Daniel
    - Sonata (chorus), 1931
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Sandoval, Miguel
    - Picture of man and wife conversing (piano), 1945
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Santa Cruz, Domingo
    - Three pieces for violin and piano, 1939
      - Publisher's proofs (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold
    - Klavierstück, 1932
      - Printed scores (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Seeger, Ruth Crawford see Box 3, Crawford, Ruth
  - Sessions, Roger
    - Duo for violin and piano, 1942
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Seymour, John Lawrence
    - Three romances for violoncello and piano. From the far-off hills, op. 47, no. 1, 1947
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Printed score and part (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Three romances for violoncello and piano. A song on the road, op. 47, no. 2, 1947
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Printed score and part (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Veni creator: op. 37, no. 2 (voice, organ/piano), 1947
      - Holograph manuscript scores, Versions for medium and high voice. (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Publisher's proofs, Versions for medium and high voice. (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Shevitz, Arnold
    - Improvisations: for unaccompanied flute, 1953
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Shifrin, Seymour
    - Four cantos (piano), 1948
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 3/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Siegmeister, Elie
    - The strange funeral in Braddock: for baritone and piano, 1933, Words by Michael Gold.
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Correspondence, Includes two letters from Siegmeister. (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Silberta, Rhéa
    - Jeunesse (voice, piano), 1945, Text by Marjorie White.
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Lullaby for Judith (voice, piano), 1945, Text by Marjorie White.
      - Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Slonimsky, Nicolas
    - Studies in black and white (piano), 1929
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Still, William Grant
    - Bells (orchestra), 1944
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Poem for orchestra, 1944
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Suite for violin and piano, 1945
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Holograph manuscript violin part (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Strang, Gerald
    - Eleven (piano), 1931
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Fifteen (piano), 1932
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Intermezzo: 2nd movement of a symphony, 24b, 1935
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Percussion music for three players, 1935
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Strongin, Theodore
    - Four duos for two flutes, 1948
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Tansman, Alexandre
    - Four piano moods, 1944
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Thatcher, Gladys Knesel
    - Then I remember (voice, piano), 1953
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Thomson, Virgil
    - Capital, capitals: for four men and a piano, 1947, Text by Gertrude Stein.
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Sonata da chiesa (clarinet, horn, trombone, trumpet, viola), 1926
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/8)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Toch, Ernst
    - Fuge aus der Geographie (chorus), 1930
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Correspondence, Includes two letters from Vladimir Ussachevsky. (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Ideas: op. 69 (piano), 1947
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Poems to Martha: op. 66 (voice, string quartet), 1943
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Quintet, op. 64 (piano quintet), 1938
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Serenade, op. 25 (2 violins, viola), 1943
      - Parts, Revised edition. (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Tremblay, George
    - Piano sonatas, op. 8, nos. 1-2, 1939
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Trusselle, Stanley
    - I hear my Father speak (voice, piano), 1953
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Uribe Holguín, Guillermo
    - Preludio, op. 49, no. 1 (piano), 1939
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Preludio, op. 49, no. 1 (piano), 1939, This and the above work are both listed as being op. 49, no. 1 but are different works.
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Preludio, op. 56, no. 1 (piano), 1939
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Van Vactor, David
    - Miscellaneous vocal works, 1944
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Varèse, Edgard
    - Density 21.5 (flute), 1946
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Ionisation (percussion ensemble), 1931
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Notes and corrections (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Vaughan, Clifford
    - Bonny Mary (voice, piano), 1944
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 11/8)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Veprik, Alexander Moiseevich
    - Stalinstan (chorus, piano), 1934
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Text (English translation) (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe
    - La traviata. Prelude to Act III (string orchestra), 1946, Arrangement by William Harris.
      - Manuscript score in the hand of Harris (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Vernon, Ashley
    - Lü Hsing. The journey (voice, piano), 1942
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 11/9)
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/9)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Villa-Lobos, Heitor
    - Melodia da montanha: Serra da Piedade de belo horizonte (piano), 1942
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/10)
    - New York sky-line (piano), 1942
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Correspondence, Includes five letters from Henry Cowell. (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Wagner, Richard
    - Tristan and Isolde. Introduction to 3rd act (string orchestra), 1946, Arrangement by William Harris.
      - Manuscript score in the hand of Harris (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Printed score and parts (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Weber, Ben
    - Closing piece: for organ, op.36, 1955
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 12/1)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/1)
      - Correspondence, Includes one letter from Weber and two letters from Vladimir Ussachevsky. (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Dance for unaccompanied cello, op. 28, 1948
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Five bagatelles for piano, 1939
      - Publisher's proofs (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Legend: for violin and piano, 1938
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Webern, Anton
    - Geistlicher Volkstexte. Liebste Jungfrau, wir sind dein, op. 17 (voice, violin, clarinets), 1930
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Weiss, Adolph
    - Six preludes for piano, 1929, Nos. 1-2, 6, 9, 11-12.
      - Publisher's proof (Box-folder 12/4)
      - Printed scores (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Sonate for flute and viola, 1930
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Wilkinson, Marc
    - Three pieces for cello and piano, 1952
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Wolff, Christian
    - For prepared piano, 1951
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 12/6)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Wolpe, Stefan
    - Passacaglia for piano solo, 1936
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Printed score paste-up (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Holograph manuscript notes (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Woronoff, Wladimir
    - Sonnet pour Dallapiccola (piano), 1948
      - Manuscript score paste-up (Box-folder 12/8)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Wright, Norman
    - When lilacs last in the dooryard bloomed: President Lincoln's burial hymn (voice, piano), 1945, Text is Leaves of grass by Walt Whitman.
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 12/9)
      - Publisher's proofs (Box-folder 12/9)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/9)
    - An inscription by the sea (voice, piano), 1945, Text by Edwin Arlington Robinson.
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Publisher's proofs (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Unidentified composers
    - Untitled piano music, circa 1953
      - Holograph manuscript fragments (Box-folder 12/11)
      - Publisher's proof fragments (Box-folder 12/11)
- Miscellany, 1944-1948 (Box 12)
  Published New Music catalog, handwritten list of composers/titles included in New Music, and publisher shop tickets for music not included in the collection.
  Arranged by type of material, and alphabetically by music title therein.
    - New Music published catalog, undated (Box-folder 12/12)
    - New Music handwritten list, undated (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Shop tickets, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 12/12)